# Syed Zeeshan Ali (MCS, MCP)

gecezeeshan@gmail.com | http://www.linkedin.com/in/gecezeeshan

#### **Profile**

Software development team lead with over 13+ years of experience in all phases of SDLC, focusing on conceptualizing business needs and translating them into viable technical solutions. Strengths include successful analysis and problem-solving expertise, highly rated oral and written communications skills, and proven project management experience. Strong background in Microsoft Technology development environment has provided the opportunity to work on a diversity of software projects, especially focusing on database analysis and design. Sound in managing and implementing DEVOPS operations using azure platform. Good work ethics with excellent communication and interpersonal skills.

## Experience

DEVELOPMENT TEAM LEAD | CONTOUR SOFTWARE | SEPTEMBER 2014 - PRESENT My responsibilities include but are not limited to:

- · Conducting meetings with clients to demonstrate work-in-progress on a regular basis.
- · Getting a daily status report to client as well as a weekly report detailing a review of the tasks completed
- Recruiting, Hiring and Train across teams, know every team member's strength and weakness and works with them to ensure a positive outcome.
- Ensure agile principles to ensure successful project deliveries.
- · Analyzing risks, issues and progress to report to both the client and higher management.
- Creating opportunities for the company to gain more business as well as helping the client achieve what he
  needs.
- Encouraging, arranging, motivating and conducting training and refresher sessions for the resources to get to know new technologies as well as better ways to do common things
- Working closely to mitigate issues including but not limited to leaves, annual leaves planning, curricular activities, annual appraisals and career planning.

#### TEAM LEAD/SCRUM MASTER | CONTOUR SOFTWARE | SEPTEMBER 2014 – AUGUST 2018

- Conducting pre-start meetings with managers.
- · Analyzing the requirements and selecting appropriate resource for the job.
- Ensuring and conducting scrum meetings (daily scrim, planning, review, backlog grooming, and retrospective meetings) to ascertain agile process.
- · Working closely with more than one client via Email, Phone or IMs like Skype etc.
- · Working with resources to get client's requirements translated, planned and completed in a timely and accurate way.
- Ensuring that the developer understands and communicates with his client well.
- Ensuring that the client gets timely responses from developer(s) and they delivery exactly what was being expected.

#### PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE ENGINEER| SHAMS SOFTWARE | APRIL 2011 - APRIL 2014

- · Worked on health care products ranging from CRM to android apps.
- · Requirement gathering and collaboration within team to ensure successful project delivery.
- · Implement CI/CD for smooth product delivery.

## SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER | ALGORITHM CONSULTING | AUGUST 2010 – MARCH 2012

- · Developed various ERP modules of textile industry ranging from import/export to finance.
- · Provided support on multiple projects and accommodate client requirements using agile.

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER | NET2APPS TECHNOLOGY | JUNE 2007 - AUGUST 2010

- Involved in designing, developing, and installing software solution by following software development lifecycle.
- · Investigates problem areas and provided support.

## Education

MASTERS IN COMPTER SCIENCE | SEPTEMBER 2017 | MUHAMMAD ALI JINNAH UNIVERSITY, KARACHI

BACHELORS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE | FEBRUARY 2017 | VIRTUAL UNIVERSITY OF PAKISTAN

MICROSOFT CERTIFICATION | 480 - PROGRAMMING WITH HTML5 WITH JAVASCRIPT AND CSS3 | FEB 14, 2013

MICROSOFT CERTIFICATION | 412-CONFIGURING ADVANCED WINDOWS SERVER 2012 | AUG 20, 2014

### **Technical Skills & Abilities**

- TECHNOLOGIES: ASP .Net, .Net Core, NodeJS, IOS Development, ERP, CRM, DotNetNuke.
- SERVER-SIDE LANGUAGES: C#, VB.net, C++, Objective C, PHP, Coldfusion, LINQ, SPA.
- · CLIENT-SIDE LANGUAGES: JavaScript, JQuery, Express, React, Angular, JQueryMobile.
- FRAMEWORKS: ASP.Net, Angular, KnockoutJS, MVC, EntityFramework.
- · DATABASE: SQL Server, MongoDB, MySQL, SQLITE.
- **DESIGNING**: Sass, CSS, HTML5, Bootstrap, Photoshop.
- · OTHERS: JSON, AJAX, XML, XSLT, WebServices, DEVOPS.

# **Projects**

**Home builders:** warranty management System (<a href="www.homeinformationpackages.com">www.homeinformationpackages.com</a>). Survey Application for buyers (<a href="http://customer-connect.ca">http://customer-connect.ca</a>), customer insight (<a href="http://customerinsight.ca/">http://customerinsight.ca/</a>)

Health Care Projects: Physician Office Solutions, Patient Kiosk, ezWayFinder, EzDictate, E-Learning.

Textile ERP Solution: Inventory Management, Import Bond, GatePass, Finance Module, Procurement Module.

**Human Resource:** Fippex, Net2Invoice, Net2Survey

Others: 4Tanslation (<u>www.4translation.com</u>)